KELLY McDonald

San Francisco, CA • (248) 207-1933 • kmac200@me.com • Kelly McDonald | LinkedIn

CHIEF PRODUCT OFFICER

Expanding innovation and corporate vision with proven, multi-industry leadership and execution

At once revolutionary and pragmatic, an entrepreneur and experienced executive differentiated by 20+ years of building both successful products and the businesses that harness their ability to expand reach, relevance, and revenue. Technical and analytics expertise that underpins the ability to conceive and create customerpleasing enhancements with urgency. Strategic prowess that sees what pieces and people are needed, and a knack for hiring that fills those gaps with passionate talent that runs to work each day to make things better than they were yesterday. A personable coach dedicated to fine-tuning strengths and finding opportunities for team members to thrive. Broad-view organizational leadership matched by deep strength in steering Sales, Operations, and Product.

- Strategic Planning & Execution
- Business Development
- Change Management
- Tailored Team-Building
- Customer-Focused Operations
- Process Improvement
- Platform Creation & Enhancements
- Market Research & Analysis
- M&A Due Diligence & Integration
- Digital Tool Development



"If Kelly were to write an Art-of-the-Deal sort of book, she would a) actually write it herself, and b) it would probably be called 'The Art of the Doable.'

That's what she's all about as a senior executive: assessing the situation, deciding what's possible, and then making it happen with unbelievable drive and a high degree of predictability. Few sales and operations execs know how to effectively work with engineers, and Kelly is one of them."

G. Linetsky, CTO, TrueAccord

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2021 to Present • CIPIO.AI • SAN FRANCISCO, CA

Delivering true Community Commerce Automation for 21st Century marketers looking to connect with buyers over shared values and lifestyles

Chief Product Officer

Serves as the domain expert for a cutting-edge influencer engagement platform created and sold to a former client now using it as a company centerpiece. Leads as both a scrappy strategist and a key executive, steering the Product & Design team as well as overseeing Client Success. Played a pivotal role in a smooth acquisition transition, optimizing the diverse experiences of team members, cultivating energy and mutual respect, and fostering a mindset of continuous improvement.

- Launched new platform and reached \$500K ARR within six months.
- Expanded the platform to include more than 130M+ influencer profiles in the user profile store, and brought on new clients including notable clients World Gym, Resort Pass, Crunch Fitness, Icon Park, Righteous Felon Jerky and Botanic Choice.
- Built out new tools, using data science and machine learning products for more precise search and discovery. Rolled out a
 first to market Natural Language Processing, image-to-image discovery tools, and a prescriptive content suggestions tool.
- Created visual heat maps for content suggestions revealing where a consumer's eyes track when they look at an image.
- Devised a proprietary Brand and Audience Scoring Model (Cindex), assessing brand health in addition to influencer potency.
- Created a Lookalike Scoring Model, enabling replication of a talented influencer by using their profile to find a similar match.
- Launched VibeCheck- a social media caption generator powered by the GPT-3 leading to clients seeing a 54% increase in social reach in first quarter over quarter results.

KELLY McDonald PAGE 2

2018 to 2021 • KYNDOO • SAN FRANCISCO, CA

A data intelligence company revolutionizing influencer marketing, solving industry issues of safety and fraud

Chief Executive Officer / Founder

Ideated and created the data and the platform to help move the social influence industry from being a marketing "side-hustle" to the highest-producing revenue channel at any organization. Answering the data problem of whether an influencer has a credible, relevant and reachable audience, allows brands to find and engage the perfect fit – and prevent fraud in the space.

- Took the entrepreneurial leap quickly after conceiving the idea and acquired initial revenue within months. Garnered support from elite technology innovators 500Global and TechCrunch.
- Built a data store of 80M user profiles with a combined audience exceeding 2.5 billion.
- Introduced and refined the Kyndex Kyndoo's propriety scoring model moving influencer assessment beyond mere demographics to deeply segmented, quantifiable audience data.
- Hired a CTO and amassed an initial team of 10 specialists, eventually engaging executives and advisory board members who hail from Shutterfly, Match.Com, Universal Studios, Bayer, Doctors.com, Ketchum, Airwallex, and OpenX.
- With early product adoption and clients including Amazon's PillPack, Inc., PlushCare, and California Olive Ranch, raised \$500K in VC and angel funds from groups including 500Global, Atland Ventures, and Gaingels.com.
- Created a 14-point "brand safety check" that scans influencer posts and data for captions, images and context. The results analyze an influencer's likelihood of creating controversial content that may not align with brand values, including profanity, nudity, violence, divisive language, or sensitive social topics.
- Led the Kyndoo team through acquisition by CIPIO.ai, securing roles for all employees.

2016 to 2018 • REALTY SHARES • SAN FRANCISCO, CA

An \$870M real estate investment platform giving investors direct access to quality opportunities and real estate operators the ability to raise capital

Senior Vice President, Revenue & People (2018) | Vice President, Sales & Operations (2016 to 2018)

Joined this commercial real estate crowdfunding startup to establish the residential debt side of the business. As employee No. 30, and the first in Residential, created and scaled the team and product line from the ground up. Helped achieve Series C funding and scale the organization to serve 88K accredited investors in the commercial real estate investment industry. Managed 14 direct reports including 5 Senior Directors and 2 Vice Presidents.

- Scaled the Residential staff from 0 to 15, with lending/processing teams facilitating \$180M in closed volume in 18 months.
- Following an integral role in the sale of the Resi debt book of business to Lima One Capital, shifted to running the Equity side of the business. Managed the team and operations, as well as Business Development, Sales Enablement, and the Investor Relations and People teams.
- With an eye for closing gaps with automation, built an internal product that processed investors with reduced approval time, allowing the optimization of funds previously stalled in limbo. Increased balance sheet turn-time 4X and revenue by \$230K.
- Established Realty Shares' OKR goal-setting framework and KPIs.
- Assumed the fast-growing company's Head of People role a spot open for a year and created an entirely new organizational chart, including job descriptions and needed leveling for 130 employees. Brought critical structure to interview processes and implemented the company's first promotion and review cycle.

2014 to 2016 • MOVOTO REAL ESTATE • SAN MATEO, CA

The country's second-largest online real estate broker

Vice President, Sales & Operations

As the first VP hired, led the charge to turn operations teams into sales-generation specialists and steered the accompanying technical transformation that bolstered those efforts.

- Managed the build of an agent app that, instead of texting leads to agents, would hand off live leads. Served as Product Owner for the platform, which decreased lead acceptance time from 40 minutes to less than five. Led cross-functional team in bringing on 93% of real estate agents within 30 days of rollout to the app store.
- Elevated total lead conversion by 50% through the "Say Yes" campaign, changing the business model to reduce lead contact time and scrubbing all referrals before hand-off.
- Increased total commissions earned per sale from the partner agent network, leading to a 17% growth in overall revenues.
- Leveraged personal network to facilitate lead-generating partnerships with Lending Tree, United Wholesale Mortgage, Quicken Loans, and National General Insurance.
- Led the successful campaign to move client service and operational teams to a Honduras-based partner with a dedicated remote structure, which scaled to 200 people, reduced internal costs, and increased the conversion of agent-referred leads.

"Kelly's passion and energy is contagious. She knows how to build a happy and productive team that is incredibly motivated a strong and effective leader who manages to infuse fun in everything she does – even difficult conversations. Combine that with incredible knowledge and expertise in sales, teambuilding, and educating, and she's

StartOut Growth Lab

> 500 Global, Batch 26

> TechCrunch Include 100

Nova Innovation's 2021

Endorsed by Neil Patel's

Angels & Entrepreneurs

Media Tech

Winner for Innovation &

GrowthMarketingPRO

actually unstoppable."

KELLY McDonald Page 3

2013 to 2014 • RME360-RESPONSE MARKETING EXCELLENCE • TAMPA, FL

A direct marketing firm helping financial advisors and insurance professionals meet accredited investors

Vice President, Sales Operations (2013 to 2014) | Sales Director (2013)

Revitalized a tenured sales team and optimized operational processes, managing sales and client-facing operations teams to produce 4K+ monthly marketing campaigns on a multichannel platform achieving \$17M in net revenue for 2013. Managed sales forecasting, planning, budgeting, key metrics analysis, HR activities, and opportunity identification.

- Led the financial services sales team to 43% YOY growth with the organization's largest corporate client.
- Saved the company \$2.5M+ in lost revenues with a quick response to challenges presented by a new list vendor.
- Recommended changes to sales roles, coverage models, and team configurations to maximize sales productivity.
- Fostered a deep-rooted team culture, which drove increased revenues and helped the sales team achieve both professional and personal goals. Served a key role in developing sales incentive compensation programs to provide competitive pay.
- Improved order process implementation and reduced monthly revenue roll from a historic 11% to 8%.
- Managed the integration of the ShoreTel phone system with Salesforce to allow real-time call coaching and click-to-dial calling.

2011 to 2012 • My Insurance Expert • Troy, MI

A start-up selling term life insurance in the wake of the Affordable Care Act

Sales Training Manager/Sales Director

Fully embraced the energy, community, and vision of a Series B start-up, recruited by a Quicken colleague to develop and steer sales processes/training at all levels. Made exacting financial decisions and managed the Training & Quality Assurance team, focused on high-quality, consistent client interactions, increasing close rates, and facilitating cross-selling by monitoring and reinforcing the sales process.

- Worked with trainers and team leaders to develop the team's ability to reduce cost-per-acquisition and increase revenue.
- Conducted one-on-one development sessions with team members on the sales floor.
- Led four-week training proving ground program to provide new team members with hands on, real life environment training.
- Listened in on live calls, coaching advisors via Five 9. Took over calls when necessary to second-voice and close clients.

2009 to 2011 • SHORE MORTGAGE/UNITED WHOLESALE • BIRMINGHAM, MI

A private, multi-level mortgage lending company closing billions in residential home loans

Director of Sales Training & Business Development

Provided both sales training and operational leadership in transforming a brick-and-mortar business into a national platform. Reporting directly to the President and Board Chairman, stood up a national call center and navigated the momentous challenge of teaching well-tenured employees to do business over the phone instead of in person.

- Redesigned and implemented ongoing training for new and veteran loan officers, triggering a 127% increase in production.
- Steered multiple projects, including the acquisition of a more functional lead management system, the implementation of a
 call recording system, and operational systems to process and shorten lead-to-funding time. Also introduced and executed a
 new CRM system.

2005 to 2009 • QUICKEN LOANS • DETROIT, MI

The nation's leading mortgage lender, a \$36B company achieving the highest ratings for both customer and employee satisfaction

Executive Banker & Lieutenant Director of Mortgage Banking

While maintaining a \$3M personal production standard, helped lead a team of 20 in daily operations and the monthly close of \$40M+ in loans. Thrived as an impactful coach, influencing in one-on-one sessions and large group training.

- Developed a 60-day program for new bankers that helped them win early and resulted in the region's lowest turnover rate.
- Created and led a client campaign that increased referrals from 30 to 100+ a month.
- Called in with an elite group of bankers to restructure and recapitalize alt-loans to conventional loans during the peak of 2008 mortgage crisis.

Regional Sales Coach

After rapid promotion, authored and implemented a sales process that homed in on rapport-building questions beyond mortgages. Taught and trained across two regions, leading skills sessions for 200+ and increasing deals closed monthly by bankers.

Senior Mortgage Banker

Closed 30+ deals a month with clear, direct communication, effectively helping clients get to the heart of their issues. Recommended loan approvals and denials based on application reviews. Consistently exceeded sales goals by 20%.

EDUCATION

Editor, Third Coast Literary Art Magazine

Founded Morebucks.org, a P2P textbook exchange marketplace, and successfully exited to the university upon graduation

TECHNOLOGY

Python | HTML5 | CSS | JavaScript | Unity C# | Salesforce | HubSpot